Guide to the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center records, 1990-2004.
Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center records, 1990-2004
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center records, 1990-2004.
23-27-3234
New York State College of Human Ecology,Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center.
2.4 cubic ft.
Publications, office documents
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes historical information, committee meeting minutes, reports, publications and files concerning grants, symposiums and visiting scholars.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center is a university-wide umbrella organization that houses the Cornell Institute for Translational Research on Aging. Past institutes included the Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute, the Cornell Gerontology Research Institute and the Pathways to Life Quality Study. The center is named in honor of Urie Bronfenbrenner, Professor Emeritus of Human Development and Psychology at Cornell.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes historical information, committee meeting minutes, reports, publications and files concerning grants, symposiums and visiting scholars.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology,; Bronfenbrenner, Urie, 1917-; Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute.; Cornell Gerontology Research Institute.; Cornell Institute for Translational Research on Aging.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Human Development.; Pathways to Life Quality Study.
Subjects:
Human ecology--Research.; Family--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Additional material and digital versions can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/11731
SERIES LIST
Series I. Grants
Series II. Charter
Series III. History
Series IV. Organizational Charts/Directories
Series V. Committees
Series VI. Reports/Plans
Series VII. Publicity
Series VIII. Publications
Series IX. Stationery
Series X. Distinguished Speakers and Visiting Scholars
Series XI. Colloquia/Symposia
Series XII. Family Business Research Institute/Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Grants
  - IRP funding announcements (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - IRP evaluation sheets/guidelines (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IRP Funding lists/charts, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - IRP memos (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - IRP-Bisogni, et al., 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Spring
  - IRP-Eloundou-Enyegue, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - IRP- Wang, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - IRP-Avery, et al., 2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - IRP-Kenkel et al., 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - IRP-Lillard, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - IRP-Maxwell, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - IRP-Cassano, et al., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - IRP-Greene, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - IRP-Lounsbury, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - IRP-Peters, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - IRP-Brooks, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Fall
  - IRP-Allen, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - IRP-Kritz, et al., 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - IRP-Williams, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - IRP-Green, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - IRP-Kenkel, et al., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - IRP- Pillemer, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - IRP-Kutty, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - IRP-Evans, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Fall/Spring
  - IRP-Garbarino, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - IRP-Raver, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - IRP-Williams, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - IRP-Rendall, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - IRP-Sobal, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - IRP-Devine, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - IRP-Kutty, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - IRP-Rendall, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - IRP-Fields, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - IRP-Lillard, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - IRP-Stycos, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - IRP-Avery, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - IRP-Haugaard, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - IRP-Canfield, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - IRP-Latham, et al., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - IRP-Eckenrode, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - IRP-Olds, et al., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - IRP-Pillemer, et al., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - IRP-Devine, et al., 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - IRP-Wethington, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - IRP-Moen, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Training Grants (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Series II. Charter
  - Charter (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series III. History
  - History - General (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - History - Proposal To Establish an Aging/Gerontology Program, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2A)
  - History, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - History, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Life Course Institute (1992) and various other outreach programs - concerning budgets, 1993-2000 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Series IV. Organizational Charts/Directories
  - Organizational Charts/Directories (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series V. Committees
  - Steering, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Steering, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Steering, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Steering, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Steering, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Steering, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Steering, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Steering, Pre-1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series VI. Reports/Plans
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 23A)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Annual Reports/Plans, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 29A)
  - Pathways to Life Quality-Overview, Reports, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Series VII. Publicity
  - Newspaper Clippings, Press Releases, 1994-2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Series VIII. Publications
  - Publications - Articles by Phyllis Moen, Francille Firebaugh, Donna Dempster-McClain, 1995-2003 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Brochures- about the BLCC, the Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute, Life Course Institute and the Gerontology Certificate Program (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Newsletters, 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Issue Briefs, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Cagri News"-Newsletter of the Cornell Applied Gerontology Research Institute, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lend a Helping Hand, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lifelines, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Women's Roles, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Partners in Caregiving: Cooperative Communication Between Families and Nursing Homes, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Brochure about the Family Business Research Institute (Box 3)
  - Brochure - Examining Pathways to Individual and Family Well-Being, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Brochure about the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center and about the Cornell Careers Institute, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Pathways to Life Quality - Kendal Progress Report, 1998-05 (Box 3)
  - The Cornell Couples and Careers Study, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute Final Report - Funded by the Alfred Sloan Foundation, 1999 (Box 3)
  - How Family Friendly is Upstate New York?, 2001 (Box 3)
  - The Cornell Midcareer Paths and Passages Study, 2001 (Box 3)
  - The New "Middle" Work Force, 2004 (Box 3)
- Series IX. Stationery
  - Report Covers/News (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Small paper (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Labels (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Folders (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Envelopes (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Letterhead - From Various Programs in the BLCC (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Series X. Distinguished Speakers and Visiting Scholars
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - McKinlay and McKinlay, 1995-04-13 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Antonucci and Jackson, 1994-03-10 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Gould, 1993-05-07 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - McLanahan and Garfinkel, 1993-05-04 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Riley and Riley, 1992-04-27 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Deborah Smith, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Jeffrey A. Chesky, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series XI. Colloquia/Symposia
  - Colloquia (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Colloquia, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Colloquia, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Colloquia, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Colloquia, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Colloquia, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Colloquia, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Colloquia, 1992-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Symposia - Rethinking Work, Family, and the Life Course, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Symposia - Williams, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Symposia - Bronfenbrenner, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Symposia - Household Time Use, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Series XII. Family Business Research Institute/ Cornell Employment and Family Careers Institute
  During the mid to late 1990's, the Family Business Research Institute was a major institute within the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center. FBRI was directed by Ramona Heck, J. Thomas Clark Professor of Entrepreneurship and Personal Enterprise. Ramona served on the Steering Committee for the Bronfenbrenner Life Course Center.
  - Proposal - "A Life Course Approach to Working Families: A Research and Training Agenda" by Phyllis Moen, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Family Business Research Institute Executive Summaries, Memos, Sample Focus Group Memo, Sample in Department Interview, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 26)